在本节中，我们将讨论测量磁场。一个简单而且
In this section, we’re going to talk about measuring the magnetic field. A simple and
熟悉的磁场传感器类型是磁罗盘。指南针被发现了
familiar type of magnetic field sensor is the magnetic compass. The compass was discovered
由中国人在2000多年前。它包含一个与之对齐的磁化针
by the Chinese over 2,000 years ago. It contains a magnetized needle that aligns with the
地球的磁场。地球围绕穿过北方的轴旋转
Earth’s magnetic field. The Earth rotates about an axis that passes through the North
南地理极点。地球本身是一个巨大的磁铁和北方和南方
and South geographic poles. The Earth itself is a gigantic magnet and the North and South
磁铁的磁极不对应地球的北极和南极地理极点。
poles of the magnet do not correspond to the North and South geographic poles of the Earth.
我们可以想象这个巨大的内部磁铁传出的磁场线
We can imagine the magnetic field lines from this giant internal magnet passing out of
行星表面，穿过太空，然后潜入地面
the surface of the planet, arcing through space, and then diving back in to the ground
在北磁极。我拿着的红色箭头代表
at the North magnetic pole. The red arrow that I’m holding represents
大约是地球的一个磁场线。我们可以把这些想象成想象的
approximately one of the Earth’s magnetic field lines. We can think of these as imaginary
从地球出来的线，穿过天空，再次降落在北极
lines which come out of the Earth, arc through the sky and land again at the North Pole of
星球。现在，我通过测量地球的三个组成部分来对齐这个箭头
the planet. Now, I have aligned this arrow by measuring the three components of the Earth’s
使用我的手机磁场。而且，此刻，我有这个箭头和手机的方式
magnetic field using my phone. And, at the moment, the way I have this arrow and the phone
取向，非零的磁场的唯一组成部分是Y方向，即
oriented, the only component of magnetic field that’s non zero is in the Y direction, that’s
我的这个方向，在我的手机上。地球的磁极是不断的
the, this direction on my, on my phone. The magnetic poles of the Earth are constantly
移动，这对于像指南针指向的传感器来说有点问题
moving and that’s a bit problematic for a sensor like a compass which points at the
磁极。我们需要了解磁极的位置
magnetic poles. We need to understand something about where the magnetic poles are with respect
地理极点以及它们如何移动。指南针指向指针
to the geographic poles and how they are moving. The needle of a compass points towards the
这个星球的磁北极。但是，真正的北方或地理北方是不同的
Magnetic North Pole of the planet. But, true North or geographic North is in a different
方向。在这里，我们有一个右手坐标框架，其中轴指向地理位置
direction. Here, we have a right-handed coordinate frame where the axes are pointing to geographic
北部，地理东部，垂直向下朝向地球的中心。想象一下吧
North, geographic East and vertically down toward the center of the planet. Imagine now
包含磁场矢量的平面，用红色箭头和符号B表示。
a plane that contains the magnetic field vector which is denoted by a red arrow and the symbol B.
该平面与地理北方向之间的角度是磁偏角D.
Angle between this plane and the geographic North direction is the magnetic declination angle D.
该图显示了磁偏角
This diagram shows magnetic declination for
2010年，我们可以看到它在全球范围内变化很大。磁性
the year 2010 and we can see that it varies quite significantly across the planet. Magnetic
北方可以与真正的北方相差正负20度。这些价值变成了
North can be up to plus or minus 20 degrees away from true North. These values become
我们可以非常清楚地看到南磁极附近非常极端
quite extreme in the vicinity of the South Magnetic Pole which we can see very clearly
这里。如果你正在驾船并且你正在使用航海图，那么适当的磁力
here. If you’re sailing a boat and you’re using a nautical chart, the appropriate magnetic
赤纬通常标记在该图表的某处。磁偏角变化
declination is typically marked somewhere on that chart. Magnetic declination varies
随着时间的推移，这个引人入胜的视频显示了磁偏角的等高线
over time and this fascinating video shows the contour lines of magnetic declination
在数百年的时间里变化。
varying over periods of hundreds of years.
磁场线通常不平行于地球表面。
The magnetic field lines are generally not parallel to the surface of the Earth.
在南半球，磁场线
In the Southern Hemisphere, the magnetic field lines
走出地面。并且，在北半球，磁场线消失
come out of the ground. And, in the Northern Hemisphere, the magnetic field lines disappear
进入地面。因此，我们可以引入另一个角度，称为磁倾角
into the ground. So, we can introduce another angle which is referred to as magnetic inclination
通常用符号I表示并且表示磁场的角度
denoted typically by the symbol I and that represents the angle of the magnetic field
相对于地球表面的线。而且，这是磁倾角的图
line with respect to the surface of the Earth. And, this is a map of magnetic inclination
在地球表面。使用的符号约定是北半球中心。因此，如果
over the surface of the planet. The sign convention used is Northern Hemisphere centric. So, if
磁场线下降到地面，考虑倾斜角度
the magnetic field line is descending in to the ground, the inclination angle is considered
要积极。这是另一张图表，这张图表显示了磁场的强度
to be positive. Here is another chart and this one shows the strength of the magnetic
场，磁场矢量的大小，这是纳米特斯拉的单位。那是
field, the magnitude of the magnetic field vector and this is units of nano teslas. That’s
10到特斯拉减9。相比之下，现代MRI机器具有磁场强度
10 to the minus 9 Tesla. For comparison, a modern MRI machine has a magnetic field strength
约4至8特斯拉。这比磁力强十万倍
of around 4 to 8 Tesla. That’s a hundred thousand times stronger than the magnetic
地球的场强。
field strength of the Earth.